parentpay.com 2016-12-06

# Privacy policy | Parentpay

**_ParentPay Privacy  Policy_**

ParentPay Limited regard your privacy as important and any Personal Information you give to us will be used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. We do not store any Personal Information about individuals who visit the [www.parentpay.com](http://www.parentpay.com/) website, except where those individuals provide contact information or use one of our online services, such as the secure Parent Portal application. We will provide the ParentPay Portal to you on the basis of the Information that you have provided. You agree to provide accurate Information and to update any changes to your Information

Any Information you provide will only be used for the reasons specified, and will not be shared with any third party without your consent, unless required by law or unless required for the provision of services contracted for, or used by you.

We will amend or delete any Personal Data relating to you that are found to be incorrect or out of date. If you are aware of any changes that should be made to your Personal Data, please update them via the Parent Portal or contact us as detailed below as soon as possible. You can request a copy of the details that we hold about you for a small fee.

**Using Information**  
The Information that we collect is used for the following purposes,  
• the verification of your identity where required  
• for the prevention and detection of crime, fraud and anti-money laundering  
• to provide you with the service activated and registered for  
• for the ongoing administration of the service  
• to allow us to improve the products and services we offer to our customers  
• to offer new products and services to you  
• for research and statistical analysis including payment and usage patterns  
• to enable us to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations

We will retain your information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purpose(s) above, and in accordance with the law.

**Disclosing and sharing Information**  
We will only disclose your information to other parties in the following limited circumstances  
• where we are legally obliged to do so, e.g. to law enforcement and regulatory authorities  
• where there is a duty to disclose in the public interest  
• where disclosure is necessary to protect our interest e.g. to prevent or detect crime and fraud  
• in order to provide the services used by you e.g. the processing of card payments  
• where you give us permission to do so e.g. on an application form

We use reputable agents (data processors) to fulfil services on our behalf, e.g. payment service providers and acquiring banks for the authorisation and settlement of credit and debit card transactions. We will provide information to those agents specifically for use in connection with those services. The information that we provide to them will be protected by a confidentiality agreement and is to be used solely for fulfilling the service. These agents are certified to the relevant payment industry international data security standards, are required to process the information in accordance with the DPA, and will only do so in accordance with our specific instructions. We use a third party hosting company to manage the servers and store the data and for the data subject's assurance, this company is ISO27001 accredited. They do not access any ParentPay data for the purposes of providing their services to us.

**Management Information**  
We collect statistical data about usage of our websites. This information is not used to identify individuals, but is collected to provide us with an understanding of the areas of interest on our site and how our site is being used. If you are connected to the internet you will have an IP Address. This may take the form of a figure, such as 444.333.22.1. The address will be automatically  
collected and logged as part of the connection of your computer to our web server and may be used to determine the total number of visits to each part of the site. This data is not collected and used for other purposes.

**Cookies**  
ParentPay Limited may sometimes use cookies. We comply at all times with the ePrivacy Directive including the most recent changes to the law. For more information, please read about our Use of Cookies.

**Links**  
Our Website contains links to other websites. ParentPay is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites or organisations, and recommends you consult the privacy information on those sites.

**Changes to this policy**  
This policy will be reviewed and updated versions will be posted on the Website.

**Further information**  
To request a copy of the data held about you, or if you would like more information about Data Protection in ParentPay, contact:  
The Data and Information Security Officer  
ParentPay Limited  
Ricoh Arena  
Phoenix Way  
Coventry  
CV6 6GE  
Tel:02476 994 820

Requests for data access will normally be responded to within 40 calendar days of receipt. ParentPay charges a fee for dealing with a data access request and will not provide the data until the fee has been received. The current fee is £10 and should be sent by cheque made payable to “ParentPay Limited” to the address above, along with the data access request.

Before servicing the request, ParentPay will need to verify the identity of the subject making the request and in doing so may require copies of formal identification and proof of address. Where requests made by a parent are for data related to their child, ParentPay will refer to the guidance from the ICO in respect of children’s rights to their own data. Where deemed necessary, ParentPay may decide to consult with the Data Controller (e.g. the school) before complying with the request, in order to ensure data security and to help protect the data subject.
